<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>loan &#8211; FR Cam Britannica</title>
	<atom:link href="https://fr.cam.britannica.com/tag/loan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://fr.cam.britannica.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 10:40:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://fr.cam.britannica.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/FR-Cam.png</url>
	<title>loan &#8211; FR Cam Britannica</title>
	<link>https://fr.cam.britannica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>This is the last chance to save Sri Lanka, said the country&#8217;s governor</title>
		<link>https://fr.cam.britannica.com/2023/07/07/this-is-the-last-chance-to-save-sri-lanka-said-the-countrys-governor/</link>
					<comments>https://fr.cam.britannica.com/2023/07/07/this-is-the-last-chance-to-save-sri-lanka-said-the-countrys-governor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kobilakaert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 10:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sri Lanka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the economy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fr.cam.britannica.com/?p=46</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka&#8217;s central bank governor Nandalal Weerasinghe said the last chance to rescue the country from a cycle of economic disaster is underway. If action is not taken now, there will be no chance to save the country. He said these things in an interview given to the French news agency AFP at his office [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="6c20d4e4-59bf-4c7d-a489-5b417f37a3b1">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p><span>Sri Lanka&#8217;s central bank governor Nandalal Weerasinghe said the last chance to rescue the country from a cycle of economic disaster is underway. If action is not taken now, there will be no chance to save the country. He said these things in an interview given to the French news agency AFP at his office in Colombo on Thursday.</span></p>
<p><span>Nandalal Weerasinghe said that he had warned Sri Lanka about the economic disaster a few years ago. He was then the Lieutenant Governor of Sri Lanka. But then no one heeded his warnings. In such a situation, Nandalal took early retirement and moved abroad. But last year, after Sri Lanka fell into dire economic straits, he was brought back to rescue the country from disaster and was given the job of governor of the central bank.</span></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="dbe83306-6156-489e-b266-78f60bf900b5">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p><span>Nandalal Weerasinghe, 63, believes the plans he has drawn up are the last chance to save Sri Lanka from economic disaster.  </span></p>
<p><span>Nandalal told AFP, &#8216;No more excuses can be given this time. There will never be a second chance to do what we have to do now. In this case, I think the crisis has created an opportunity.&#8217;</span></p>
<p><span>Gotabaya Rajapakse was elected president of Sri Lanka in 2019 on popular promises to lower tax rates. At that time, Nandalal Weerasinghe was the second top official of the country&#8217;s central bank.</span></p>
<p><span>After Rajapakse took office as president, he began printing large amounts of currency in an attempt to reduce the rate of profit. In this, the amount of government debt continues to increase.</span></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="5df0f50f-f62a-46eb-b4d2-35c79191bd0d">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p><span>Nandalal Weerasinghe said, &#8216;I always raised my concerns when I was senior lieutenant governor.&#8217;</span></p>
<p><span>However, the Rajapakse administration and other officials of the central bank did not pay attention to his objections. Nandalal Weerasinghe said, due to the situation, he felt he had no choice but to retire early.</span></p>
<p><span>&#8220;I saw that the way the policies were being implemented, the situation would worsen. At that time the kind of situation I had predicted would happen.&#8217; said Weerasinghe.</span></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="b290829b-48bb-4386-b4b6-7b3688e707b6">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p>Later, the banker migrated to Australia with his family after taking early retirement. He lived there in secret. Played golf five days a week. However, Rajapakse asked him to return to the country to take the helm of the central bank amid the extreme economic disaster of Sri Lanka last year.</p>
<p>Rajapakse fled the country in July. Ranil Wickramasinghe took over as the President of Sri Lanka. He approached the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to save the country from disaster.</p>
<p><span>Even before last year, Sri Lanka had 16 agreements with the IMF. But in the end the country failed to fulfill the promises.</span></p>
<p><span>Weerasinghe believes that if Sri Lanka sticks to the IMF&#8217;s current program, its economy will return to normal within two to four years. If the country were to turn to any other program, it would be very difficult and ultimately fatal.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fr.cam.britannica.com/2023/07/07/this-is-the-last-chance-to-save-sri-lanka-said-the-countrys-governor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
